Guide to the UH Women's Resource Center Records
University of Houston Libraries
UH Women's Resource Center Records
2004-2008
2012-009
University of Houston. Women’s Resource Center
0.50 Linear Feet
Special Collections, University of Houston Libraries
This collection includes materials related to the UH Women’s Resource Center. The collection is broken into four series: General Information, Advertisements, Organizations and Printed Materials.
Historical Note:
The Women’s Resource Center (WRC) opened on Tuesday, March 9, 2004 as a result of the recommendations of the University Commission on Women (UCW). In September 1999, President Arthur K. Smith appointed 24 UH-affiliated women to the Presidential Commission on the Status of Women for a two-year period to address the issues and concerns of women on the University of Houston campus. The Commission was created to examine the lack of women in higher administrative positions and the workplace climate for women on campus. The Commission was later expanded to include men. The Commission’s first action was to undertake a campus-wide survey and developed a report with numerous recommendations, one of which was the creation of a university supported Women’s Resource Center. The recommendation was realized with the opening of the WRC in 2004.
The goals of the WRC are to provide a comfortable place where UH students, staff, and faculty can seek information on a variety of topics, obtain confidential referrals to appropriate campus and community resources, and discuss issues of concern; to educate the University of Houston community on topics that concern women with a special focus on violence against women due to gender, sexual identity, race, or disability; to identify and research issues that affect University of Houston women; to serve as a liaison between women on campus and the administration, often by working with the University Commission on Women; and to celebrate the achievements of University of Houston women by featuring a UH female faculty, staff or student each month on our web site in the "Spotlight" feature.
Access Terms
This Collection is indexed under the following controlled access subject terms.
Corporate Name:
University of Houston; University of Houston. Women's Resource Center
Genre/Form of Material:
Advertisements; Correspondence; Fliers (printed matter); Minutes
Acquisition Information:
University of Houston Women’s Resource Center, September 2012
Conditions Governing Access:
Open for research.
Related Materials:
University Commission on Women Records (http://archon.lib.uh.edu/index.php?p=collections/controlcard&id=534)
Scope and Contents
This collection includes materials related to the UH Women’s Resource Center. The collection is broken into four series: General Information, Advertisements, Organizations and Printed Materials.
Detailed List of Contents
- General Information
  Scope and Contents
  This series contains materials directly related to the WRC. Included are meeting minutes, articles about the center and various other materials pertaining to the organization.
  - Advisory Board Meeting, February 1, 2005 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Advisory Board Meeting, July 12, 2005 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Articles, undated (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Certificate from Gov. Rick Perry, 2004 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - End of Year Report FY04, 2003 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Mentoring Program, April 30, 2008 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Open House Guest Book, 2004, 2006 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Various, 2006-2008 (Box 1, Folder 8)
- Advertisements
  This series consists of advertisements placed in the Daily Cougar, the University of Houston daily newspaper. The materials consist mainly of advertisements of events held by the WRC.
  - Announcements, 2005-2008 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Books, 2007-2008 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Charity, 2006, 2009 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Events, 2004-2007 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - General Information, 2005-2006 (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Lectures, 2004-2007 (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - Open House, 2006-2007 (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - Theater, 2004-2008 (Box 1, Folder 16)
- Organizations
  This series contains materials related to organizations with which the WRC worked closely. Both organizations, like the WRC, focus on support and networking of women on the University of Houston campus.
  - Coog Women at Work, 2006-2007 (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - Women’s Network, 2006 (Box 1, Folder 18)
- Printed Materials
  This series consists of printed materials not directly related to the WRC. Transitions is a magazine for new students.
  - Evening Student Services Brochure, undated (Box 1, Folder 19)
  - Transitions Vol. 17, Summer 2007 (Box 1, Folder 20)